If you want to know one of Ashito Aoi's biggest weaknesses, it's how narrow the scope of his
strategies are. He only plans for what's in front of him. He wants to be considered the
leader of the team. Wants to be the one who makes all the big goals. I want. That's his
creed. It's all about him. He's the classic self-centered player. He sees no options beyond
his own game, which won't work. Because the fundamental shape in soccer is the triangle.
It takes three players to do anything.
what he's just trying to buy time again because we scored i don't believe that crap for a minute
hey shit heel want me to snap your neck in half or what
back in the 11 on 21 game you said something let's just focus on the basics
it made a lot of sense okay and during that match all we were doing was relying on the numbers
so that logic resonated with us it turned out the whole point of the exercise had nothing to do with
numbers it was about whether we could play the game or not and how well no matter how many we
were up against besides soccer's fundamental shape is the triangle everyone knows that
it's always been drilled into us since we were juniors yeah i get it at least i think i do
are you saying you were trying to build a triangle like with me it doesn't matter
you may have initiated the move but you didn't understand the core concept of the triangle
that was obvious you never even looked at us because you wanted to be the one to get the goal
am i right once i had noticed that we were out of options i signaled for you to send the ball out
towards the wing well you just passed it back to me instead and that's when my pass got intercepted
and they countered why didn't you tell me i did oh think about it we always talk about the importance
of triangles during training sessions you've heard it mentioned at least once daily it's a key element
of our gameplay maybe you thought it was too simple to be real or that we were just speaking in metaphors
or maybe you didn't care either way if so we never had a chance even if we had been spelling
it out for you the whole game long you just simply wouldn't have bothered to retain the information
for all the promoted players who had to claw our way up here your attitude is impossible to understand
not that we really care to i'm pathetic i'm begging you teach me how to play soccer your way
you gotta believe me i love this game so much that i can promise i begged all our coaches to teach me how
to play from scratch but i guess i should have asked my teammates instead
i understand it now though in order to become a better player i need to absorb everything that i see
thank you both of you for helping me seriously thank you for teaching me soccer
so then how how did you improve so quickly okay listen up you guys game's restarting you see those
three those are the ones we have to contain if we do their team won't function we're still in the lead
by only one goal all this time i thought soccer was about carrying the ball at your feet towards the
goal and being the one to make that goal but i was wrong you need two other players and the three of you
form a triangle then as a unit you work to slide the triangle into the opposition's part of the field
you tempt the other team toward us and that creates a space it's just a tiny gap
but it's plenty of room for one tip of the triangle to sneak in to put pressure on us and fill the space
we've created other players come across to cover next you pass the ball around the triangle to get the
other team moving more tiny gaps start to accumulate and that creates a larger space in the opposition's
half damn it wow wow this is amazing if we keep this up how many goals could we score
what the what
oh don't lose him
ah
i knew it they moved exactly the way i thought this is what i envisioned
oh
impressive he restructured the triangle oh hey guys
he moved the players at the tip without them knowing he just replaced kuroda with otomo yeah that was a
pretty gutsy move all right
ashito
that was so bizarre and now i just feel weird
it's like i saw it suddenly i could see what everyone was gonna do
on both teams
every move
so clearly like it already happened
ashito killed that goal was something just now but it was asari and otomo who combined for the score
aoi made it possible he did a dummy run from left to right across the area
so it looked like the final pass was going to him
sekyo high was obviously wariest of the three on the left wing
that's why they sent two players across at once to challenge aoi
but that was the whole plan he deliberately lured the two players toward him so that he could clear a path for otomo to make the goal
what's more that wasn't their original play
aoi showed asari what was happening as he moved towards otomo
right as he was running past he communicated by using a quick hand signal
it was subtle but he pointed right at otomo
i saw it that kid legit controlled everything
just in this match alone not only as he grasped the concept of triangles but he's actually built on it
how is that even possible it seems so far-fetched
we're into extra time just three minutes left let's tear him open score one more goal and we win
protect the goal even if you have to rough him up we gotta keep the score tied
that day they were all going at each other day of the entrance ceremony i remember ashito drew
something weird on the blackboard only those of us who noticed stayed after to check it out
wait this isn't accurate is it the placement of the players around me is correct though
same with the ones around me oh come on that is a bit of a leap no one's memory is perfect he can't
know all of your placements yeah you're right it's crazy talk but i've been thinking about it a lot
it's true the speed of ashita's progress is no joke
his basics are pathetic but once he gets something down the dude owns that skill
he's able to put it to use right away nobody masters a technique that fast ever seems like
he has some kind of i don't know extraordinary instinctual ability the thing is he might have
a unique skill it's possible that he can predict the movements of each player just think the sheer scale of
it you seriously believe he can memorize the placement of players on the field and now
you think he has a superpower to predict every move during gameplay isn't that fun come on man
you know batter those kinds of ridiculous illogical fantasies have no place in the world of soccer
right is it that illogical though really anyway i'm not gonna waste my time dwelling on some drama
i've been so excited about getting to see ashito in action ever since i first saw him play at the
tryouts
we're almost out of time but i oh i feel like my brain is shutting down
i'm starting to see weird things and my head's getting fuzzy
excuse me but can i please have that ball
oh damn it all this sucks they're bringing on subs to eat up time they're totally going for
the draw yes i'm already you there's no time left maybe enough for one more play hey
you need to calm down
i'm sorry
thanks this next goal's for you
ashito let me take the throw in here okay i need you to play up at the front
uh
triangles eye contact
i learned a whole different side to soccer and it's awesome use the players around you
and be sure to score as a team but that's just a general rule i'll still make goals
i'll take it one step further and use my head
let's all attack now
defend the goal let's go what how are we supposed to do that do we need to stick more players on
those three we've already tried that he ended up leaving that midfielder unmarked and he scored for
them that means they changed play mid-game pick and coordinate new moves with any player on the field
what do we do who do we pick up who are we supposed to mark i'm on to you
he's the one who started this it could have been simple but he decided to change his play out of
nowhere then everything went downhill we should have taken him out sooner
off the knee
play on
don't get drawn out stay back their tactic is just to draw you out stay put don't you leave that goal
all i need is just to bring myself
that's all i need just bringing myself is enough
you know what this was fun i had a great time
the right side's totally open yeah it is
how come none of them are going over there
they don't know it's clear to us because we're seeing it from above the view from their level is
very limited so try not to be mad at the players doesn't this feel like a dream
being able to see and know where the players are from above it's as if you're a bird in flight
circling over the field and yet it's not a dream it's just rare but there are players that exist in
in the world who can do precisely that
well if nothing else he's interesting to watch
I was killing it!
Man, I'm really good!
We're on one!
Well, if nothing else, he's interesting to watch.
Yep.
Akutsu hardly ever mentions other players,
but he mentioned this one, so I am intrigued.
Very intrigued.
The most fascinating part is that he seems completely unaware of what he can do.
Seiki Ohai was pathetic.
Too wary and obsessed with defending deep.
They didn't address the space that opened up for mid-range shots.
But no one could have guessed how much they'd upped their game in the second half.
Maybe not even them.
Quite a feat.
Well, isn't this rare?
You complimenting someone, I mean.
All right, so all of you that are in Asperion Youth's B Team,
you guys went against Sekio High yesterday,
and we congratulate you!
Looks like the A Team also won over in Aomori Prefecture.
They're all on their way back now,
but I'm feeling like the B Team should definitely be allowed to begin celebrating without them.
So Kydo Electric is hosting this victory celebration party for you!
Yay!
Thank you to our main sponsor!
What are you waiting for?
Dig in!
într V12
.
Hmm.
Whoa!
So tender!
I can't take it!!
Hmm.
It melts when you bite into it!
I hardly chewed any of it.
And at the same time, the juices seeped into my mouth!
Dude, just shut up and eat!
That is all wrong!
What are you talking about, Hana?
What's wrong?
Christie-ing can make or break meat.
a Korean novo-barbecue ribs have loads of fat,
have loads of fat, grill right,
and they'll be easier on your stomach.
What? No frickin' way!
Grill one side about 80%, the other about 20%.
It'll give it a nice, crispy texture.
Wow.
Oh, oh, uh, I'm sorry.
Uh, please?
Don't mind me, I'm no one.
Yeah, right, you're the manager's baby sister,
so I'd hardly call you no one.
Wait, what? Didn't know you knew each other.
Are you serious?
She's been helping us out since we were
on the junior youth team.
We're in the same grade,
so all the promoted players know her.
Hmm.
No way, is that true?
Then I hope that means I'll get to keep seeing you
at our games.
We're gonna win the next one.
Anyway, Asari, you wanted to say something to Aoi and the others, right?
Uh-uh.
During our first day,
I might have, um, said some...
I might have gone a little too far.
I'm sorry.
Huh?
Uh...
I wasn't there to hear it, but...
I know friendships are made stronger
after rupture and repairs.
This is how we grow together and build a foundation.
Today's a brand new day.
Let's start over.
That goes for you, too, Otomo.
Are you guys ready?
Let's play soccer!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, Aoi, I was thinking...
Huh?
I mean, since we were talking about the fight,
you said something to us that day
that has stuck with me ever since.
Stop obsessing over goals?!
I'm a forward!
If I stop obsessing, then I'm done!
I thought that was really cool.
Maybe those of us promoted from junior youth
think more about the theory of soccer
rather than the way it's actually played.
But you're not bound by those theories.
I think I can really learn a lot from you.
Thank you.
Whoa!
Is that Kurabayashi?!
Huh?
He's finally out?
Where?
Now, this kid's only a second year in high school.
He's 16 years old
and has been called
Esperion Youth's hidden gem.
Haruhisa Kurabayashi
making his debut on the J1 stage.
Fans love him!
From that alone,
you can tell he's an exceptional player.
People say that he's the future star
of not only Esperion,
but Japan's national team!
Look at how calm he is!
So much confidence in front of 20,000 people!
It's amazing!
Hello, Aoi.
Huh?
Excited to see him play.
My name's Enri Kaido.
We share a class.
Huh?
I was wondering,
would you be interested in trying some image training?
Huh?
Try to follow just Kurabayashi's movements.
He's good to watch since he's a high school student like you.
Observe his behavior around the pros.
Now picture in your mind what you'd be doing
if you were in his place.
Visualize it.
And then,
please describe to me what you're seeing.
Huh?
Next time on Awashi, turn.